Guide to Woman’s Baptist Missionary Society of New Lisbon papers, 1885-1926.
Fenimore Art Museum
Woman’s Baptist Missionary Society of New Lisbon papers, 1885-1926.
1885-1926 [bulk, 1885-1920]
This collection, which encompasses over 40 years of women’s activities relating to the Woman’s Baptist Missionary of New Lisbon, Otsego County, NY and later, the Woman’s Baptist Home and Foreign Missionary Society of New Lisbon consists of Minute Books, financial documents, an educational notebook focusing on hygiene, a program from the Northfield Summer School for Women's Foreign Missionary Societies, and recipes.
.25 cu. ft.
Woman’s Baptist Missionary Society of New Lisbon, 1885-1912.; Ladies Auxiliary Society of New Lisbon, 1912-
Fenimore Art Museum Research Library 80 Lake Road Cooperstown, NY 13326
Coll. No. 452
NM-15.2013
Acquisition Information
Coll. No. 452 is open for research according to the regulations of Fenimore Art Museum Library.
Access Restrictions
In 1876, the Woman’s Baptist Missionary Society of New Lisbon, Otsego County, NY was organized to aid “in the work of the Christian Elevation of women in foreign lands.” The group raised money in a variety of ways, making contributions to the church for improvements and decorations, and to Baptist missionary projects. In August 1912, the “Foreign and Home missionary societies were combined.” Thereafter, until at least 1920, the New Lisbon society was known as the “Woman’s Baptist Home and Foreign Missionary Society.”
Biography/History
Woman’s Baptist Home and Foreign Missionary Society.; Women in missionary work.; Women in missionary work.; Women--Societies and clubs.; Accounts; church records; Flyers (printed matter); Invoices (financial records); minutes (administrative records); recipes; reports; rosters; School notebooks
This collection, which encompasses over 40 years of women’s activities relating to the Woman’s Baptist Missionary of New Lisbon, Otsego County, NY and later, the Woman’s Baptist Home and Foreign Missionary Society of New Lisbon consists of four Minute Books, 1876-1887, 1888-1897, 1898-1905, and 1910-1920. These minute books contain the society’s constitution, slate of officers, minutes of quarterly and annual meetings, and membership and dues lists. The 1910-1920 Minute Book also includes receipts and other financial documents.
Scope and Contents
Additionally, the collection contains: financial documents including bills, invoices, financial reports, receipts, and statements related to the Woman’s Baptist Missionary and the Woman’s Baptist Home and Foreign Missionary societies, 1891-1926; an educational notebook belonging to Mrs. C. L Talbot, possibly daughter or sister of the Treasurer/Secretary of the society, topics include: Dietetic, Effects of Alcohol and Tobacco, Care of the Eyes, Lungs and Respiration, and 4th Grade Geography, u. d.; handwritten manuscript and printed program from the Northfield Summer School for Women's Foreign Missionary Societies, 1919; and recipes for Baby Pap, Anna Reynold’s Sour Cucumber Pickle, Cocoa to Drink, Home Made Cream Cheese, and Creamy Candy Base.
- 451.1/1 Educational Notebook, Mrs. C. L. Talbot., u.d.
- 451.1/2 Financial documents, 1891 - 1926
- 451.1/3 Financial documents, Ladies Auxillary Society., 1898 - 1902
- 451.1/4 Membership lists., 1885, u.d.
- 451.1/5 Minute Book., 1876 - 1887
- 451.1/6 Minute Book., 1888 - 1897
- 451.1/7 Minute Book., 1898 - 1905
- 451.1/8 Minute Book., 1910 - 1920
- 451.1/9 Minutes, Ladies Aid., November 30, 1938 - March 28, 1939
- 451.1/10 Recipes, u.d.
- 451.1/11 Report and Program, Northfield Summer School for Women's Foreign Missionary Societies., 1919